A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management, 1995-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management, 1995-2009
The Library of Virginia
50781
10 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Virginia. Dept. of Human Resource Management
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years (Code of Virginia 42.1-78). Types of records restricted include but are not limited to: personal information (2.2-3801). These records have been minimally processed and it will be necessary for an archivist to review and remove or redact confidential records or information before the records can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies can be made. If you are planning to use these records, please contact Archives Reference Services for more details prior to planning your research trip.
Acquisition Information
Accession 50781 transferred by Anne F. Waring, James Monroe Building, 101 N. 14th St., Richmond, Va., 15 March 2013.
Accruals
The Library of Virginia has multiple accessions for the correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management and will continue to receive accruals for this ongoing series.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Division of Personnel was established by the provisions of the Virginia Personnel Act passed by the General Assembly on April 1, 1942. The Division was replaced by the Department of Personnel and Training in accordance with an act passed by the General Assembly on April 12, 1976. Another name change occurred as of July 1, 2000 when the Department of Personnel and Training was changed to the Department of Human Resource Management.
The department is charged with establishing a uniform and effective personnel management system for state employees based on objective methods of appointment, training, promotion, transfer, layoff, removal and discipline. The department also provides expertise in the areas of compensation, equal employment compliance, health benefits, grievance procedures and training. The Governor is the chief personnel officer of the state by statute, but his authority has been delegated to the director of the Department of Human Resource Management.
As part of a reorganization of the executive branch of state government, the Dept. of Employment Dispute Resolution was eliminated by the General Assembly (SB 678) effective July 2012 and its duties were transferred to the Dept. of Human Resource Management. This bill also eliminated the Virginia Council on Human Resources and authorized the Director of the Dept. of Human Resource Management to convene ad hoc working groups to address issues relating to the state workforce.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and subject files, 1995-2009, of the Director of the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management. Includes correspondence between the Director and other members of the government of Virginia as well as subject files relating to projects undertaken by the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management. There are also reports submitted to the General Assembly and material relating to various professional organizations in the field of human resources.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence and subject files
Wherever possible, the original order of the files has been maintained.
Contents List
- I. Correspondence and subject files, 1995-2009.
  - 1995-2009 (Accession 50781)., Extent: 10 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
    Correspondence and subject files, 1995-2009, of the Director of the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management. Includes correspondence between the Director and other members of the government of Virginia as well as subject files relating to projects undertaken by the Virginia Department of Human Resource Management. There are also reports submitted to the General Assembly and material relating to various professional organizations in the field of human resources.
    - Integrated Human Resource Information Systems Council on User Support, 1997-2000. (Box 1)
    - Integrated Human Resource Information Systems Line Agency Business Processes, 1997-2000. (Box 1)
    - Integrated Human Resource Information Systems, 1997-2000. (Box 1)
    - Incentive Plan Alternate Dates, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Incentive Plan Public Safety Secretariat, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Incentive Plan, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Workforce Transition Act: RTP, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Workforce Transition Act, 1995-1997. (Box 2)
    - Workforce Transition Act: State Police, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Workforce Transition Act Audit Report, 1997. (Box 2)
    - Layoff Policy, 1995. (Box 2)
    - Operation Review: Travel, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Health Benefits, 2010. (Box 3)
    - National Association of State Personnel Executives Nominating Committee, 2010. (Box 3)
    - National Association of State Personnel Executives Executive Committee, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Performance Budgeting Steering Committee, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Performance Budgeting Steering Committee, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Consumer Driven Health Plan, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Government Reform, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Operation Review: Insurance, 2010. (Box 3)
    - Layoff Policy, 2010. (Box 3)
    - National Association of State Personnel Executives, 2008-2009. (Box 4)
    - Virginia Community Development Corporation Board, 2008. (Box 4)
    - Virginia Enterprise Applications Program, 2007. (Box 4)
    - Virginia Health Care Alliance, 2007. (Box 4)
    - Health Initiatives, 2006. (Box 5)
    - Public Health Emergency, 2006. (Box 5)
    - Telework, 2007. (Box 5)
    - Final Government Performance Project, 2007. (Box 5)
    - Meeting with Wayne Turnage, Governor's Chief of Staff, 2007. (Box 6)
    - Long Term Care Program Options, 2007. (Box 6)
    - Virginia Health Care Alliance, 2007. (Box 6)
    - Meeting of Agency Heads and Legislative Liaisons, 2008. (Box 6)
    - Report of the Department of Human Resource Management Workers' Compensation Program Settlements in Fiscal 2007. (Box 6)
    - HR at a Glance, 2006. (Box 6)
    - Operations Reviews, 2007-2008. (Box 6)
    - National Association of State Personnel Executives Mid Year Conference, 2006. (Box 6)
    - Productivity Investment Fund Oversight Committee, 2008. (Box 6)
    - COVA High Deductible Health Plan, 2006. (Box 7)
    - Small Agencies Study, 2003. (Box 7)
    - Cabinet Study, 2003. (Box 7)
    - National Association of State Personnel Executives Workforce Planning, 2004. (Box 7)
    - Emergency Management Plan, 2004. (Box 7)
    - HR Council - The Beginning, 2001-2003. (Box 7)
    - HR Council - Minutes, 2003-2004. (Box 7)
    - Appointed HR Council Members, 2005. (Box 7)
    - Healthy Virginians, 2007. (Box 8)
    - Veterans in the State Workforce, 2002. (Box 8)
    - Virginia Civil Rights Memorial, 2008. (Box 8)
    - Governor's Town Hall Meetings, 1998-2008. (Box 8)
    - Pan Ex 07, 2006-2007. (Box 8)
    - Virginia Offender Workforce Development, 2007. (Box 8)
    - MS150 Governor's Cup, 2006. (Box 9)
    - CVC Campaign, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Legislative Services, Division of, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Agency Fraud, Waste, and Abuse Hotline, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Agreements and Contracts, 2007. (Box 9)
    - Auditor of Public Accounts, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Budget Plans, 2007. (Box 9)
    - Commonwealth Competition Council, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Commonwealth Managers Association, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Virginia Community College System, 2004. (Box 9)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Department of, 2006. (Box 9)
    - Council of State Governments, 2007. (Box 9)
    - Budget: DHRM Cost Allocations, 2007-2008. (Box 9)
    - Workforce Transition Act, 1995. (Box 10)